<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-24T10:13:26+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Hitchiker’s guide to the galaxy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/guidetothegalaxy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hitchiker's guide to the galaxy" /><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/guidetothegalaxy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/guidetothegalaxy.html">&lt;p&gt;Leiðarvísir puttaferðalangsins um Vetrarbrautina er vísindaskáldskapur eftir Douglas adams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The various versions follow the same basic plot but they are in many places mutually contradictory, as Adams rewrote the story substantially for each new adaptation. Throughout all versions, the series follows the adventures of Arthur Dent, a hapless Englishman, following the destruction of the Earth by the Vogons, a race of unpleasant and bureaucratic aliens, to make way for an intergalactic bypass. Dent’s adventures intersect with several other characters: Ford Prefect (who named himself after the Ford Prefect car to blend in with what was assumed to be the dominant life form, automobiles), an alien from a small planet somewhere in the vicinity of Betelgeuse and a researcher for the eponymous guidebook, who rescues Dent from Earth’s destruction; Zaphod Beeblebrox, Ford’s eccentric semi-cousin and the Galactic President; the depressed robot Marvin the Paranoid Android; and Trillian, formerly known as Tricia McMillan, a woman Arthur once met at a party in Islington and the only other human survivor of Earth’s destruction thanks to Beeblebrox’ intervention.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Douglas</name></author><summary type="html">Leiðarvísir puttaferðalangsins um Vetrarbrautina er vísindaskáldskapur eftir Douglas adams.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">War of the Worlds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/War_of_the_Worlds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="War of the Worlds" /><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/War_of_the_Worlds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/War_of_the_Worlds.html">&lt;p&gt;The War of the Worlds(Innrásinn frá Mars) er vísindaskáldskapur eftir H. G. Wells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With H.G. Wells’ other novels, The War of the Worlds was one of the first and greatest works of science fiction ever to be written. Even long before man had learned to fly, H.G. Wells wrote this story of the Martian attack on England. These unearthly creatures arrive in huge cylinders, from which they escape as soon as the metal is cool. The first falls near Woking and is regarded as a curiosity rather than a danger until the Martians climb out of it and kill many of the gaping crowd with a Heat-Ray. These unearthly creatures have heads four feet in diameter and colossal round bodies, and by manipulating two terrifying machines – the Handling Machine and the Fighting Machine – they are as versatile as humans and at the same time insuperable. They cause boundless destruction. The inhabitants of the Earth are powerless against them, and it looks as if the end of the World has come. But there is one factor which the Martians, in spite of their superior intelligence, have not reckoned on. It is this which brings about a miraculous conclusion to this famous work of the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wells</name></author><summary type="html">The War of the Worlds(Innrásinn frá Mars) er vísindaskáldskapur eftir H. G. Wells.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ég man þig</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/egmandig.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ég man þig" /><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/egmandig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/egmandig.html">&lt;p&gt;Ég man þig er hryllingsbók/sakamálabok eftir Yrsu Sigurðardóttur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ungt fólk sem er að gera upp hús á Hesteyri í Jökulfjörðum um miðjan vetur fer að gruna að þau séu ekki einu gestirnir í þessu eyðiþorpi. Á sama tíma dregst ungur læknir á Ísafirði inn í rannsókn á sjálfsmorði eldri konu. Hún virðist hafa verið hugfangin af syni hans sem hvarf fyrir þremur árum – og fannst aldrei.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Þessir ólíku þræðir fléttast saman í grípandi sögu þar sem rómaðir hæfileikar Yrsu til að kveikja spennu og magna upp dulúð njóta sín til hins ítrasta.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Yrsa</name></author><summary type="html">Ég man þig er hryllingsbók/sakamálabok eftir Yrsu Sigurðardóttur.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Einvígið</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/einvigid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Einvígið" /><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/einvigid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/20/einvigid.html">&lt;p&gt;Einvígið er sakamálabók eftir engan annan en Arnald Indriðason&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sumarið 1972 er Reykjavík í uppnámi; heimsmeistaraeinvígið í skák er að hefjast í Laugardalshöll og bærinn fullur af útlendingum. Kalda stríðið er í algleymingi og fulltrúar austurs og vesturs fylgja sínum mönnum, Spassky og Fischer, að taflborðinu. Meðan undirbúningurinn stendur sem hæst fer meinlaus unglingspiltur í bíó og verður fyrir fólskulegri árás. Lögreglan er önnum kafin en Marion Briem, sem stýrir rannsókn málsins, einsetur sér að skilja það einvígi sem þarna er háð með lífið að veði.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Í fimmtándu skáldsögu Arnaldar Indriðasonar mynda sannsögulegir atburðir rammann um grípandi frásögn af hörmulegri mannfórn. Enginn íslenskur höfundur hefur notið viðlíka vinsælda og Arnaldur síðustu ár, hér heima jafnt sem erlendis. Bækur hans hafa verið þýddar á tugi tungumála, selst í milljónum eintaka og hlotið frábæra dóma hvarvetna. Breska stórblaðið The Guardian hefur sett nafn hans efst á lista yfir bestu evrópsku sakamálahöfunda samtímans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Arnaldur</name></author><summary type="html">Einvígið er sakamálabók eftir engan annan en Arnald Indriðason</summary></entry></feed>